Guide to the Mary Robinson Papers, 1948-2010 (bulk 1948-1985)
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Mary Robinson papers 1948-2010 (bulk 1985-2000)
University Archives, Duke University
Robinson, Mary.
0.5 Linear Feet 400 Items
Mary Robinson was a 1949 graduate of the Woman's College at Duke University. Robinson was also member of the White Duchy, the women's equivalent of the Red Friars honorary society.
Collection contains material pertaining to the White Duchy and her 1949 classmate and fellow White Duchy member, Nancy Hanks, eventual head of the National Endowment for the Arts and the National Council on the Arts, 1969-1977.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Mary Robinson Papers were received by the University Archives as a gift in 2008.
Biographical Note
Mary Robinson was a 1949 graduate of the Woman's College at Duke University. While at Duke she was honored with a membership in the Order of the White Duchy where she met fellow Class of '49 member Nancy Hanks. Nancy Hanks went on to become head of the National Endowment for the Arts and the National Council on the Arts. Robinson, Hanks, and other Duchy members of their class became lifelong friends and held reunions whenever possible.
Collection Overview
Contains material pertaining to the Order of the White Duchy and Nancy Hanks. Materials present include correspondence between Mary Robinson and Nancy Hanks, rituals surrounding the White Duchy; the Lucky Number, the newsletter of the White Duchy; clippings concerning the death of Nancy Hanks; the creation of the Nancy Hanks Center; and color photographs and slides documenting reunions, the Cashiers, North Carolina home of Nancy Hanks, and bequests to the Museum of Art from the estate of Hanks.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Woman’s College
Duke University. Woman’s College -- History
Duke University. Woman’s College -- Students
Hanks, Nancy, 1927-1983
Women -- Education -- North Carolina -- Durham -- History
Women -- Education (Higher)--North Carolina -- Durham
Related Material
Nancy Hanks Papers, 1894-1987 (bulk 1945-1983)
Duke University Archives/Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library
Order of the White Duchy Records, 1925-1968
Duke University Archives/David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Woman’s College Oral History Project Records, 2003-2006
Duke University Archives/David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Woman’s College Records, 1928-1974
Duke University Archives/David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Contents of Collection
- Mary Robinson Papers, 1948-2010 (bulk 1948-1985), (1 box)
  - Correspondence, 1950-2000 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1983
  - Correspondence Re: Nancy Hanks' death and memorial services, 1983
  - Estate of Nancy Hanks, 1983, 1985
  - Friends of the Nancy Hanks Center, 1984
  - Lucky Number, a White Duchy newsletter, 1957-1958
  - Nancy Hanks Center, undated
  - Nancy Hanks, genealogy, undated
  - Photos:
    - Bequests of Nancy Hanks to the Duke Museum of Art
    - Nancy Hanks Center [Washington, D.C.]
    - Nancy Hanks home in Cashiers, North Carolina
    - People
  - Slides
  - White Duchy, 1948-1974
  - Memoirs, 2009-2010